<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</title>
    <link>https://budrich.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 19:27:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://budrich.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>video_fyra</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/video_fyra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 19:27:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/video_fyra/</guid>
      <description>I have uploaded a long (~1 hour) video to youtube, where I show how to configure and use my layout script i3fyra.
www.youtube.com/watch?v=t4Tve-xpwus    Below are the things I added to the default i3 config file (~/.config/i3/config).
# focus replacements bindsym $mod+Left exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -f l bindsym $mod+Down exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -f d bindsym $mod+Up exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -f u bindsym $mod+Right exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -f r # tabswitching bindsym $mod+Tab exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -t r bindsym $mod+Shift+Tab exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -t l # move replacements bindsym $mod+Shift+Left exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -m l bindsym $mod+Shift+Down exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -m d bindsym $mod+Shift+Up exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -m u bindsym $mod+Shift+Right exec --no-startup-id exec i3fyra -m r # floating toggle replacement bindsym $mod+Shift+space exec --no-startup-id i3fyra -a # window rules for_window [class=&amp;quot;^.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dmenu</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/dmenu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 23:50:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/dmenu/</guid>
      <description>I use dmenu2, which is a patched version of dmenu. The main reason i use this instead of vanilla dmenu is so that I can set its appearance in Xresources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fixed_fixedsys</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/fixed_fixedsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 22:35:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/fixed_fixedsys/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why, but Fixedsys is one of my all time favorite fonts. I particularly like it as a monospaced terminal and programming font (Fixedsys is the font used on this site to display code and ASCII art). But it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been painless to get the terminal to accept Fixedsys.
The problem from the start is that the available version of Fixedsys is a .ttf font. After some digging around the Internet, I found this article on askubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>extreme_i3</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/extreme_i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 23:09:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/extreme_i3/</guid>
      <description>I finally did it! I Uploaded my i3 layout script, i3fyra. I have been working on it for almost a year. I think it works good enough to publish now. I recorded a video on how it looks like and have made a repo on github for my i3 related scripts.
www.youtube.com/watch?v=kU8gb6WLFk8    If you try it and find any bugs or have any other issues or questions, please report them on the github repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pbmic</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/src/pbmic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 22:01:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/src/pbmic/</guid>
      <description>Displays the volume of the default input (microphone) sink (pulseaudio).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pbweather</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/src/pbweather/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 21:59:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/src/pbweather/</guid>
      <description>Display info about the weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pbvol</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/src/pbvol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 21:57:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/src/pbvol/</guid>
      <description>Displays the volume of the default sink (pulse audio). Slightly modified version of the script found in polybar wiki on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pbmail</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/src/pbmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 21:52:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/src/pbmail/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not the original author of this script, It is an old modified i3blocks script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>budbar</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/budbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 21:43:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/polybar/budbar/</guid>
      <description>Polybar is a great statusbar that works well with i3 and other window managers, this is my config file. It uses some custom scripts to display some information.
ss-17-11-22-pbarro.png   In the screenshot above you can see polybar at the top of the screen. I use i3fyra to achieve the layout. Container A(vivaldi/wg) and B(irssi) are tabbed and container C is horizontally split with three urxvt instances.
I use some custom scripts to display some of the information in my polybar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>README</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/readme/</guid>
      <description>My personal Sublime Text settings, packages, guides and other sublime related stuff i collected in this folder.
license All my custom sublime things are licensed with the MIT license
Copyright (c) 2017 Nils Kvist Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;quot;Software&amp;quot;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions: The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>README</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/readme/</guid>
      <description>dotfiles dela budRich These are my dotfiles. The structure of the tree is the same as my home folder.
license All my dotfiles are licensed with the WTFPL license</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>README</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/readme/</guid>
      <description>i3ass - i3 assistance scripts This is a collection of scripts I have made to assist the usage of the windowmanager known as i3.
installation clone the repository
git clone https://github.com/budRich/i3ass.git
run the installation script
(for further instructions: ./install.sh -h)
./install.sh
usage Execute a script with the -h flag for help.
examples:
i3get -h display i3get help
i3get -v display i3get version
   script function     install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>README</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/readme/</guid>
      <description>scripts collection  &amp;ldquo;This is my scripts&amp;rdquo; - Kim Larsen
 license All my scripts are licensed with the MIT license
Copyright (c) 2017 Nils Kvist Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;quot;Software&amp;quot;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions: The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3fyra</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3fyra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3fyra/</guid>
      <description>fyra is the Swedish name for &amp;ldquo;four&amp;rdquo;.
 www.youtube.com/watch?v=kU8gb6WLFk8    .
www.youtube.com/watch?v=t4Tve-xpwus    In the first video above I show the functionality of i3fyra. The second video is a longer and more thorough walkthrough on how to use i3fyra
An advanced simple tiling layout for i3wm. The layout consists of four containers:
 A B C D  The internal layout of the containers doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3list</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3list/</guid>
      <description>This script is vital for i3fyra to work. But it can be used on it&amp;rsquo;s own or with other scripts. i3list is also used by i3run. i3list parses the output of the command: i3-msg -t get_tree and returns a long string with 43 values separated by spaces. This strange output format is made to make it possible to pipe the output to other scripts. A lot of the information is specific to i3fyra, but if i3list doesn&amp;rsquo;t find a value an X will be placed in it&amp;rsquo;s place in the output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3term</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3term/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3term/</guid>
      <description>I just made this script to keep my i3config cleaner. It probably needs tweaking if someone other then budRich uses it ;)
Launch a command in a new urxvt window Uses i3run to run or raise a window with the instancename: COMMAND. If no window is found, COMMAND is ran in a urxvt window with the same instance name as COMMAND. When the command exits window is cleared and returned to bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>user-dirs</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/user-dirs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 17:34:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/user-dirs/</guid>
      <description>I like to have the short lowercase names on my folders for easier navigation through from the terminal and it also looks cool.
homefolderspacefm.png   I have also written a guide, and recorded a video on how to achieve the Perfect Folder structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cv_en</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/cv_en/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 19:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/cv_en/</guid>
      <description>Born: 1982-10-06 Address: Per Lagerhjelmsgatan 11, 691 33 Karlskoga, Sweden Phone: +46 722 990 358 Mail: robstenklippa@gmail.com EMPLOYMENTS    CNC-operator - mill/lathe G-Drill     Programming, planning, operating Athens, Greece 2017/04–2017/07       Support Agent Lenovo/TelePerformance     Technical support agent, SAP, CRM, Office, Oracle Athens, Greece 2016/07–2016/10       CNC-operator - mill Valmet/Uniflex     Heidenhain, heavy details Karlstad, Sweden 2015/12–2016/07       CNC-operator - lathe B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the_site</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/the_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 19:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/the_site/</guid>
      <description>This site is made using the static site generator Hugo and the text editor Sublime Text, using GNU/Linux as an IDE.
I wanted a static site because cutting edge web development techniques and bloated IDE&amp;rsquo;s is not an environment I like. I have promised myself that the rendered site should only be HTML/CSS (except for google analytics and disqus). There is a lot of crazy stuff and bash scripting involved in creating the site, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect the finished site or your RAM and bandwidth usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoami</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 19:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/whoami/</guid>
      <description>My name is Nils. I live in Sweden and I play the blues. I have worked the majority of my adult life as a CNC-operator/programmer in the steel industry. As all jobs it has it&amp;rsquo;s pros and cons.
I also made an attempt in the telecom industry, as a technical support agent for Lenovo.
But now I am looking for some other way to earn a living.
I have been very interested in computers ever since I got a C64 back in the 80&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fresh_start</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/fresh_start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 19:13:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/fresh_start/</guid>
      <description>These are the steps I take to setup my work environment on a fresh install of Peppermint OS 8. Most of the steps are valid on other GNU/Linux distributions, but I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend anyone to blindly follow and install everything.
Before doing anything else i start syncing Dropbox. I start with this step because it can take up to 45 minutes, so while Dropbox is syncing there is time to install and setup other programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>perfect_folders</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/perfect_folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 17:18:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/perfect_folders/</guid>
      <description>I have tried many different ways to organize my files. I think the current setup I have is by far the best. It uses Dropbox to ensure cloud based backup and Hugo to create this site you are looking at where many of my actual dotfiles and scripts are viewable and auto-updated.
  folder structure This might look overcomplicated and hard to setup, but it actually makes a lot of sense and takes no time to setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mouseback</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/mouseback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:20:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/mouseback/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I got irritated how messy my i3 config file looked, and I researched alternative hotkey managers. I tried sxhkd and it is a fine piece of code. I got a much cleaner setup of the hotkeys and I could do stuff that i wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to do with i3.
But a couple of days ago, i realized that my i3 config could be just as clean as sxhkd by using variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>swedish_keyboards</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/swedish_keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:19:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/swedish_keyboards/</guid>
      <description>when I was working as a technical support agent I received several calls from angry men who couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the @ symbol on the keyboard. When I explained that they had to hold Alt-Gr and pressing 2 at the same time, they exploded with anger and told me to tell the technicians to make a new keyboard layout! I explained it&amp;rsquo;s an old standard and agreed it was stupid, but that it would probably never change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>me_myself_and_i3</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/me_myself_and_i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:18:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/me_myself_and_i3/</guid>
      <description>Or, how I became a tiler i3 is a dynamic window manager for X. I use i3, and I really like it. There are many similar window managers and I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried many of them. I have run and tinkered with bug.n on windows and tested awesome and dwm on GNU/Linux.
Maybe I was unlucky and had bad timing with awesome, I was very fresh on GNU/Linux and I think the awesome project was in a transition phase, but I had a hard time grasping all of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>install_i3</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/install_i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:17:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/install_i3/</guid>
      <description>You can probably install i3 directly from your distributions package manager. But If you want to be sure to get the latest version or a fork you need to download and compile the source code.
i3-gaps i3-gaps is a fork of i3 developed by Airblader who happens to be one of the main developers on vanilla/normal i3. i3-gaps has some features that is not 100% in sync with the design philosophy of normal i3, that&amp;rsquo;s why it is a fork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3_setup</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/i3_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:17:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/i3_setup/</guid>
      <description>These are some of my personal preferences and thoughts on how to configure i3. Read the official userguide often to see what options you got. I have left out a lot of functionality in my config that i don&amp;rsquo;t use.
Your config file can be located at different places depending on how you installed i3.
variables the first line of the default config file looks like this:
set $mod Mod4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>font_rendering</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/font_rendering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:15:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/font_rendering/</guid>
      <description>It is easy to get used to bad font rendering. But there are some simple steps one can take to get great looking fonts on GNU/Linux.
Below is a summary of an article on binarytides, with some spice.
download the following fonts from
http://www.google.com/fonts/
 Droid Sans Droid Sans Mono Droid Serif Noto Sans Noto Serif Open Sans  Unzip &amp;lsquo;em and place them in ~/.fonts. Download and place this: .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>profile</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 20:15:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/profile/</guid>
      <description>Nothing going on here, just sourcing my bashrc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bashrc</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bashrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 17:21:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bashrc/</guid>
      <description>The read -rsn1 -t2 input waits two seconds for a key-press before it starts X and i3. If I press 1 I stay in the wonderful tty environment. If I press 2 or wait 2 seconds, i3 starts.
I have found this method much more convenient then a normal DM, where you have to change DE from some, very easily forgotten, menu. Often resulting in me logging in to the wrong DE&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xresources</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 17:21:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xresources/</guid>
      <description>One of the most classic dotfiles, .Xresources. I have gotten most ideas on from the r/unixporn wiki. I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to get &amp;ldquo;short name&amp;rdquo; for the includes to work, which annoys me a bit..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xinitrc</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xinitrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 17:17:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xinitrc/</guid>
      <description>This is part of my anti-DM suite. The stuff I want to happen just before i3 loads up, goes here.
Starting urxvt in daemon mode is really nice and makes it consume less resources and spawn new terminal windows much faster.
I use hsetroot to set the desktop background to a minimal tiled pattern and use the background color from Xresources.
The Seba keyboard layout keeps me sane!
I also have some special options to setxkbmap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>compton</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/compton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/compton/</guid>
      <description>compton is a lightweight compositor for X that works really well with i3. A compositor adds some eye-candy like transparency and drop-shadows to the windows. But it also do some anti screen tearing magic and such. The compton setup can however be a bit tricky and it all depends on your own preferences and hardware.
The blocks below are more i3 then hardware related that you might find useful:
opacity-rule = [ # these transparency rules makes windows in tabs/stacks look good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>preferences</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/klavaro/preferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/klavaro/preferences/</guid>
      <description>Klavaro is a GTK touch typing trainer. It is really nice to just sit and listen to a pod while the fingers flow. My average WPM is around 55 at the moment. But I slowly improve.
I believe touch typing is very important to master if you want to become a good programmer.
If you never have given touch typing a thought, i really recommend you read Programming&amp;rsquo;s Dirtiest Little Secret by Steve Yegge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>config</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/i3/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/i3/config/</guid>
      <description>I have written a long article about my i3 config: i3_setup . I have made some assisting scripts, a suit I call i3ass to help me manage my window manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bud</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/irssi/bud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/irssi/bud/</guid>
      <description>I have used irssi for a long time and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever switch or finish this theme.
irssibudtheme2.png   I have tried to make it as narrow as possible, kind of how the twitch chats look. With the user name on it&amp;rsquo;s own line above the message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HatOfGod</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/colors/hatofgod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/colors/hatofgod/</guid>
      <description>This is a color-scheme &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; made many years ago. It was originally for the AHK editor SciTE. But I also ported it to Sublime and now .Xresources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>solarized_dark</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/schemes/solarized_dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/schemes/solarized_dark/</guid>
      <description>Solarized is perfect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>solarized_light</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/schemes/solarized_light/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/schemes/solarized_light/</guid>
      <description>Solarized is perfect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>solarized-dark</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/colors/solarized-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/colors/solarized-dark/</guid>
      <description>Solarized is perfect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urxvt</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/urxvt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/urxvt/</guid>
      <description>Nothing special. I really like to be able to change font (and font-size) on the fly, there are times when you want to read the output and theres times you just want to monitor the output.
I am planning to add something similar to be able to switch between a dark and light color-scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xft</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/xft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/xft/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TwoFace</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/twoface/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/twoface/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TwoFont</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/twofont/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/twofont/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>color</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/color/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/color/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3wm</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/i3wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/i3wm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>keymap</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/keymap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/keymap/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>settings</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/config/settings/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>prompt</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/prompt/</guid>
      <description>My prompt shows the runtime of the last command and a compact CWD (current work directory).
ss_time4prompt.png   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>func</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/func/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/func/</guid>
      <description>This is the power of the bash shell, you can write small functions to make using the shell easier.
lb
I found this one on the LinuxBBQ forums it adds the last command to a logfile. Very handy.
adda
Adds a new permanent alias. Example:
adda dwn cd ~/Downloads
this will add, alias dwn=&#39;~/Downloads&#39; to ~/.bash/alias and reloads ~/.bashrc so you can use the alias immediately.
apti/gemi/pipi
install packages and log package name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>misc</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/misc/</guid>
      <description>Random options, most from the default .bashrc file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>export</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/export/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/export/</guid>
      <description>Environment values and shell options</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>alias</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/alias/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TwoFace</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/packages/twoface/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:50:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/packages/twoface/</guid>
      <description>This Sublime Text package makes it possible to toggle between two different UI-appearances with the same hotkey. It is also possible to set a absolute UI. It changes both the color scheme and the UI-theme. It changes all elements of the UI defined in the settings file.
TwoFace.sublime-settings
The keys face1 and face2 is mandatory.
{ &amp;quot;face1&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;color_scheme&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Packages/Boxy Theme/schemes/Boxy Solarized Dark.tmTheme&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;theme&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Boxy Solarized Dark.sublime-theme&amp;quot; }, &amp;quot;face2&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;color_scheme&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Packages/Boxy Theme/schemes/Boxy Solarized Light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TwoFont</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/packages/twofont/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:50:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/packages/twofont/</guid>
      <description>This Sublime Text package makes it possible to toggle between two different fonts with the same hotkey. It is also possible to set a absolute font. It changes all elements of the fonts defined in the settings file.
TwoFont.sublime-settings
The keys font1 and font2 is mandatory.
{ &amp;quot;font1&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;font_face&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Hack&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;font_size&amp;quot;: 18, &amp;quot;font_options&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;no_bold&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;no_italic&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;subpixel_antialias&amp;quot;] }, &amp;quot;font2&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;font_face&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Fixedsys Excelsior 3.01-L2 Mono&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;font_size&amp;quot;: 12, &amp;quot;font_options&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;no_bold&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;no_italic&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;no_antialias&amp;quot;] }, &amp;quot;monaco&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;font_face&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Monaco&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;font_size&amp;quot;: 14, &amp;quot;font_options&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;no_bold&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;no_italic&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;subpixel_antialias&amp;quot;] }, &amp;quot;Inconsolata&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;font_face&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Inconsolata&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;font_size&amp;quot;: 20, &amp;quot;font_options&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;no_bold&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;no_italic&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;subpixel_antialias&amp;quot;] } }  user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3syntax</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/packages/i3syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:50:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/budlime/packages/i3syntax/</guid>
      <description>This Sublime Text package adds a simple syntax highlighting to the i3 config. It only adds highlighting to comments. Installing the package also adds the ability to toggle comments. You can also define &amp;ldquo;symbols&amp;rdquo; (default hotkey in sublime: ctrl+r) by making a comment in this fashion:
# &amp;gt; this is a section.
I host this package on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>igi</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/igi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:40:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/igi/</guid>
      <description>This script generates an issue file that is shown when you log in to your computer without a DM. It applies the current color scheme that you have set in .Xresources
ss_igi1.png   dependencies    toilet display ASCII artish fonts     lolcat rainbow color effect on terminal output   fortune prints a random fortune    The script has a sudo mv command, which requires you to enter a password.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3zen</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:38:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3zen/</guid>
      <description> I made a post on /r/unixporn where you can view an animated gif of i3zen in action.
Put the window between two ghosts (centered). if the window already is &amp;ldquo;zen&amp;rdquo;, move it back to its original workspace. If the window is not in zen but another window is, both of them will be zen in a tabbed container.
usage
$ i3zen [OPTION] ARGUMENT
   option argument function     -v  show version info and exit   -h  show this help and exit    dependencies  i3get i3gw  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3run</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:36:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3run/</guid>
      <description>This is a run or raise or hide script for i3wm. It looks for a window matching a given criteria.
These are the actions taken depending on the state of the found window:
   target window state action     Active and not handled by i3fyra mark and hide   Active and handled by i3fyra do nothing   Handled by i3fyra and hidden show container, activate   Not handled by i3fyra and hidden show window, activate   Not on current workspace goto workspace   Not found run command    Hidden in this context, means that window is on scratchpad/ Show in this context means, move window to current workspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3mtm</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3mtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:32:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3mtm/</guid>
      <description>When launched without options, i3mtm checks floating status of current window. If it is tiled, the window becomes floating. If it is floating, a search for marks is done, if no marks are found, window becomes tiled. Otherwise a dmenu asks for a mark to move window to. If no selection is made, window is tiled but not moved. Otherwise window is tiled and moved to selected mark.
With -m option window is treaded as if it was floating even if it is tiled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3gw</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3gw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:24:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3gw/</guid>
      <description>In the screenshot below, the windows to the right are tiled, and a ghostwindow is tiled on the left half of the screen. The other windows are floating.
ss-i3gw1.png   A Ghost window wrapper for i3wm.
i3-msg has an undocumented function (open) that creates empty containers, or as I call them: ghosts. Since these empty containers doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain any windows there is no instance/class/title to identify them, making it difficult to control them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3get</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3get/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:22:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3get/</guid>
      <description>Search for windows in i3 tree, return desired information if no arguments are passed. con_id of acitve window is returned.
usage $ i3get [OPTION [CRITERIA]]
   option criteria function     -v  show version and exit   -h  show this help   -a  currently active window (default)   -c CLASS search for windows with the given class   -i INSTANCE search for windows with the given instance   -t TITLE search for windows with title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3cast</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3cast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3cast/</guid>
      <description>Create and upload screen recordings
usage $ i3cast [-v|-h]
   option argument function     -v  show version info and exit   -h  show this help and exit    Just run the script to start the recording run it again to stop and preview the recording and perform action, (save,upload or play again). if no action is selected the recording is deleted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>subact</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/subact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 15:44:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/subact/</guid>
      <description>This is a script I wrote to automate the process of uploading scripts and dotfiles to this web site.
It analyzes the title of Sublime Text to get the filename of the currently open file.
If the file is in ~/bin (my local scripfolder), it is a scriptfile, else it is a dotfile. Depending on the type it is sent to different directories within my hugo project folder. Which is on my Dropbox.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>