<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</title>
    <link>https://budrich.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 17:34:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://budrich.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>user-dirs</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/user-dirs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 17:34:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/user-dirs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cv_en</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/cv_en/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 19:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/cv_en/</guid>
      <description>Born: 1982-10-06 Address: Per Lagerhjelmsgatan 11, 691 33 Karlskoga, Sweden Phone: +46 722 990 358 Mail: robstenklippa@gmail.com EMPLOYMENTS    CNC-operator - mill/lathe G-Drill     Programming, planning, operating Athens, Greece 2017/04–2017/07       Support Agent Lenovo/TelePerformance     Technical support agent, SAP, CRM, Office, Oracle Athens, Greece 2016/07–2016/10       CNC-operator - mill Valmet/Uniflex     Heidenhain, heavy details Karlstad, Sweden 2015/12–2016/07       CNC-operator - lathe B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the_site</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/the_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 19:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/the_site/</guid>
      <description>This site is made using the static site generator Hugo and the text editor Sublime Text, using GNU/Linux as an IDE.
I wanted a static site because cutting edge web development techniques and bloated IDE&amp;rsquo;s is not an environment I like. I have promised myself that the rendered site should only be HTML/CSS (except for google analytics and disqus). There is a lot of crazy stuff and bash scripting involved in creating the site, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect the finished site or your RAM and bandwidth usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoami</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 19:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/abouts/whoami/</guid>
      <description>My name is Nils. I live in Sweden and I play the blues. I have worked the majority of my adult life as a CNC-operator/programmer in the steel industry. As all jobs it has it&amp;rsquo;s pros and cons.
I also made an attempt in the telecom industry, as a technical support agent for Lenovo.
But now I am looking for some other way to earn a living.
I have been very interested in computers ever since I got a C64 back in the 80&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fresh_start</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/fresh_start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 19:13:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/fresh_start/</guid>
      <description>These are the steps I take to setup my work environment on a fresh install of Peppermint OS 8. Most of the steps are valid on other GNU/Linux distributions, but I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend anyone to blindly follow and install everything.
Before doing anything else i start syncing Dropbox. I start with this step because it can take up to 45 minutes, so while Dropbox is syncing there is time to install and setup other programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>perfect_folders</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/perfect_folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 17:18:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/perfect_folders/</guid>
      <description>I have tried many different ways to organize my files. I think the current setup I have is by far the best. It uses Dropbox to ensure cloud based backup and Hugo to create this site you are looking at where many of my actual dotfiles and scripts are viewable and auto-updated.
  folder structure This might look overcomplicated and hard to setup, but it actually makes a lot of sense and takes no time to setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mouseback</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/mouseback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:20:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/mouseback/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I got irritated how messy my i3 config file looked, and I researched alternative hotkey managers. I tried sxhkd and it is a fine piece of code. I got a much cleaner setup of the hotkeys and I could do stuff that i wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to do with i3.
But a couple of days ago, i realized that my i3 config could be just as clean as sxhkd by using variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>swedish_keyboards</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/swedish_keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:19:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/swedish_keyboards/</guid>
      <description>when I was working as a technical support agent I received several calls from angry men who couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the @ symbol on the keyboard. When I explained that they had to hold Alt-Gr and pressing 2 at the same time, they exploded with anger and told me to tell the technicians to make a new keyboard layout! I explained it&amp;rsquo;s an old standard and agreed it was stupid, but that it would probably never change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>me_myself_and_i3</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/me_myself_and_i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:18:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/me_myself_and_i3/</guid>
      <description>Or, how I became a tiler i3 is a dynamic window manager for X. I use i3, and I really like it. There are many similar window managers and I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried many of them. I have run and tinkered with bug.n on windows and tested awesome and dwm on GNU/Linux.
Maybe I was unlucky and had bad timing with awesome, I was very fresh on GNU/Linux and I think the awesome project was in a transition phase, but I had a hard time grasping all of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>install_i3</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/install_i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:17:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/install_i3/</guid>
      <description>You can probably install i3 directly from your distributions package manager. But If you want to be sure to get the latest version or a fork you need to download and compile the source code.
i3-gaps i3-gaps is a fork of i3 developed by Airblader who happens to be one of the main developers on vanilla/normal i3. i3-gaps has some features that is not 100% in sync with the design philosophy of normal i3, that&amp;rsquo;s why it is a fork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3_setup</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/i3_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:17:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/i3_setup/</guid>
      <description>These are some of my personal preferences and thoughts on how to configure i3. Read the official userguide often to see what options you got. I have left out a lot of functionality in my config that i don&amp;rsquo;t use.
Your config file can be located at different places depending on how you installed i3.
variables the first line of the default config file looks like this:
set $mod Mod4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>font_rendering</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/blog/font_rendering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:15:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/blog/font_rendering/</guid>
      <description>It is easy to get used to bad font rendering. But there are some simple steps one can take to get great looking fonts on GNU/Linux.
Below is a summary of an article on binarytides, with some spice.
download the following fonts from
http://www.google.com/fonts/
 Droid Sans Droid Sans Mono Droid Serif Noto Sans Noto Serif Open Sans  Unzip &amp;lsquo;em and place them in ~/.fonts. Download and place this: .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>profile</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 20:15:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/profile/</guid>
      <description>This is another keyplayer in the anti-DM suit.
The read -rsn1 -t2 input waits two seconds for a key-press before it starts X and i3. If I press 1 I stay in the wonderful tty environment. If I press 3 lightDM is launched and I enter my normal Peppermint OS desktop. If I press 2 or wait 2 seconds, i3 starts. Before this happens I have to login, in text mode and look at my issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bashrc</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bashrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 17:21:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bashrc/</guid>
      <description>Only thing going on here is a loop that sources all files in ~/.bash/ . I just upgraded Mint and it was kind enough to overwrite my .bashrc, that made me decide to have it as minimal as possible so I can easily restore it if something similar happens.
I don&amp;rsquo;t care so much about distros and I have not had any problems with Mint till this happened. But it is so poor design to overwrite .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xresources</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 17:21:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xresources/</guid>
      <description>One of the most classic dotfiles, .Xresources. I have gotten most ideas on from the r/unixporn wiki. I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to get &amp;ldquo;short name&amp;rdquo; for the includes to work, which annoys me a bit..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xinitrc</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xinitrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 17:17:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xinitrc/</guid>
      <description>This is part of my anti-DM suite. The stuff I want to happen just before i3 loads up, goes here.
Starting urxvt in daemon mode is really nice and makes it consume less resources and start much faster.
I use hsetroot to set the desktop background to a minimal tiled pattern and a fetch color from Xresources.
The Seba keyboard layout keeps me sane!
I use sxhkd to remap the back button of the mouse to backspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>compton</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/compton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/compton/</guid>
      <description>compton is a lightweight compositor for X that works really well with i3. A compositor adds some eye-candy like transparency and drop-shadows to the windows. But it also do some anti screen tearing magic and such. The compton setup can however be a bit tricky and it all depends on your own preferences and hardware.
The blocks below are more i3 then hardware related that you might find useful:
opacity-rule = [ # these transparency rules makes windows in tabs/stacks look good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>preferences</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/klavaro/preferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/klavaro/preferences/</guid>
      <description>Klavaro is a GTK touch typing trainer. It is really nice to just sit and listen to a pod while the fingers flow. My average WPM is around 55 at the moment. But I slowly improve.
I believe touch typing is very important to master if you want to become a good programmer.
If you never have given touch typing a thought, i really recommend you read Programming&amp;rsquo;s Dirtiest Little Secret by Steve Yegge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>config</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/i3/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/config/i3/config/</guid>
      <description>I have written a long article about my i3 config: i3_setup . I have made some assisting scripts, a suit I call i3ass to help me manage my window manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bud</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/irssi/bud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/irssi/bud/</guid>
      <description>I have used irssi for a long time and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever switch or finish this theme. I have tried to make it as narrow as possible, kind of how the twitch chats look. With the user name on it&amp;rsquo;s own line above the message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HatOfGod</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/colors/hatofgod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/colors/hatofgod/</guid>
      <description>This is a color-scheme &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; made many years ago. It was originally for the AHK editor SciTE. But I also ported it to Sublime and now .Xresources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>solarized-dark</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/colors/solarized-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/colors/solarized-dark/</guid>
      <description>Solarized is perfect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urxvt</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/urxvt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/urxvt/</guid>
      <description>Nothing special. I really like to be able to change font (and font-size) on the fly, there are times when you want to read the output and theres times you just want to monitor the output.
I am planning to add something similar to be able to switch between a dark and light color-scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xft</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/xft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/xft/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>color</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/color/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/color/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3wm</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/i3wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/xres/i3wm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>prompt</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/prompt/</guid>
      <description>My prompt shows the runtime of the last command and a compact CWD (current work directory). The last line of the file:
printf &#39;\e]710;%s\007&#39; &amp;quot;xft:Fixedsys Excelsior 3.01\-L2 Mono:style=Regular&amp;quot;
is a little dirthack™ to make it possible to use Fixedsys in urxvt, read more about how to setup fonts here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>func</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/func/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/func/</guid>
      <description>This is the power of the bash shell, you can write small functions to make using the shell easier.
lb
I found this one on the LinuxBBQ forums it adds the last command to a logfile. Very handy.
adda
Adds a new permanent alias. Example:
adda dwn cd ~/Downloads
this will add, alias dwn=&#39;~/Downloads&#39; to ~/.bash/alias and reloads ~/.bashrc so you can use the alias immediately.
apti/gemi/pipi
install packages and log package name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>misc</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/misc/</guid>
      <description>Random options, most from the default .bashrc file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>export</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/export/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/export/</guid>
      <description>Environment values and shell options</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>alias</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 16:37:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/dots/bash/alias/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>igi</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/igi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:40:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/igi/</guid>
      <description>This script generates an issue file that is shown when you log in to your computer without a DM. It applies the current color scheme that you have set in .Xresources

dependencies    toilet display ASCII artish fonts     lolcat rainbow color effect on terminal output   fortune prints a random fortune    The script has a sudo mv command, which requires you to enter a password.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3zen</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:38:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3zen/</guid>
      <description>put your windows in a zen mode for a zen mood When run, this script puts the active window between two ghosts (centered). if the window already is &amp;ldquo;zen&amp;rdquo;, move it back to its original workspace. If the window is not in zen but another window is, both of them will be zen in a tabbed container.
I made a post on /r/unixporn where you can view an animated gif of i3zen in action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3run</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:36:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3run/</guid>
      <description>run, raise or minimize a program depending on its state. if target window doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, a given command is launched. if target window is on another workspace, it is moved to current workspace. If target window doesn&amp;rsquo;t have focus it will be given focus. If target window has focus it will be sent to the scratchpad.
usage run i3run with ONE of the following options to define target window:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3mtm</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3mtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:32:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3mtm/</guid>
      <description>mtm = Move To Mark When launched without flags, i3mtm checks floating status of current window. If it is tiled, the window becomes floating. if it is floating, a search for marks is done if no marks are found, window becomes tiled. otherwise a dmenu asks for a mark to move window to. if no selection is made, window is tiled but not moved. otherwise window is tiled and moved to selected mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3gw</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3gw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:24:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3gw/</guid>
      <description>wrapper for the ghost window function in i3wm
i3-msg has an undocumented function (open) that creates empty containers, or as I call them: ghosts. Since these empty containers doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain any windows there is no instance/class/title to identify them, making it difficult to control them. They do however have a con_id and I found the easiest way to keep track of the ghosts is to mark them. That is what this script does, it creates a ghost get its con_id and mark it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3get</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3get/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:22:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3get/</guid>
      <description>search for windows in i3 tree, return desired information if no arguments are passed. con_id of acitve window is returned.
examples: search for window with instance name sublime_text. Request workspace, title and floating state. i3get -i sublime_text -r wtf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3cast</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3cast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3cast/</guid>
      <description> usage just run the script to start the recording run it again to stop and preview the recording and perform action, (save,upload or play again). if no action is selected the recording is deleted. uploaded recordings is also saved.
a notification is shown when upload is complete and a link is put in your clipboard.
protip
bindsym --release Mod3+Pint exec --no-startup-id i3cast
requirements    i3get to identify and the terminal (urxvt) window     i3run to run and hide the terminal (urxvt) window   urxvt terminal emulator   ffmpeg  commandline tool to record media   curl commandline tool to download and upload stuff   mpv minimal mediaplayer, used to preview recording   dmenu tool that displays a menu   xclip tool that handles clipboard events   xdotool needed to send q to urxvt, to quit the recording in a proper way   gif-is-jif  to save and upload gif format (optional)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>subact</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/subact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 15:44:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/subact/</guid>
      <description>This is a script I wrote to automate the process of uploading scripts and dotfiles to this web site.
It analyzes the title of Sublime Text to get the filename of the currently open file.
If the file is in ~/bin (my local scripfolder), it is a scriptfile, else it is a dotfile. Depending on the type it is sent to different directories within my hugo project folder. Which is on my Dropbox.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>