<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>letslinux on budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</title>
    <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in letslinux on budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 09:45:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>best_i3_img_viewer</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/best_i3_img_viewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 17:21:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/best_i3_img_viewer/</guid>
      <description>In this video I demonstrate how to spawn, sxiv - Simple X image viewer, in a certain container and make a small script that will always add all image files in a folder to the image list.
Be sure to check out gotbletu&amp;rsquo;s video about sxiv, he shows more things then I cover in this one.
Below is the script I use to open all windows in the same directory as the selected one:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>polybar_and_workspaces</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_and_workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 18:07:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_and_workspaces/</guid>
      <description>This is the first of three videos where I create a dynamic workspace indicator that displays the name (icon) of the current workspace and the total number of existing workspaces.
In this first video, we create a new hook module and create the first version of the script that will output the workspace information.
!!! The getpid script on github is a fixed version. The reason i got multiple pids was because it returned the pid of the getpid script it self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>perfect_folders</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/bashrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 09:45:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/bashrc/</guid>
      <description>This is the first video in the Let&amp;rsquo;s Linux series.
How to organize your files and folders in a sane way, with auto sync to both Dropbox and website!
Detailed article on my site:
https://budrich.github.io/blog/perfect_folders/
Dots:
https://github.com/budRich/dots
I have tried many different ways to organize my files. I think the current setup I have is by far the best. It uses Dropbox to ensure cloud based backup and Hugo to create this site you are looking at where many of my actual dotfiles and scripts are viewable and auto-updated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>workspace_wallpapers</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/workspace_wallpapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:48:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/workspace_wallpapers/</guid>
      <description>This is the last of three videos where I create a dynamic workspace indicator that displays the name (icon) of the current workspace and the total number of existing workspaces.
In this video i show a way to set different wallpapers for different workspaces.
video info:    color scheme: eighties     terminal font: Inconsolata   terminal emulator: URxvt   figlet font: 3d.flf, by xero   wallpaper: pauls-boutique    videos    https://youtu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>polybar_magic_workspaces</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_magic_workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:46:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_magic_workspaces/</guid>
      <description>This is the second of three videos in which I create a dynamic workspace indicator for polybar. The indicator will display the name (icon) of the current workspace and the total number of existing workspaces.
In this second video I add fontawesome icons to indicate which workspace we are currently viewing. I also make a small script that switch to the last active workspace or create a new workspace if only one workspace exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>uniform_qt_and_gtk</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/uniform_qt_and_gtk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:42:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/uniform_qt_and_gtk/</guid>
      <description>This is the fifth video in a series on how to setup and use my theme manager, mondo.
I use qt5ct to manage some of the appearances of Qt.
https://sourceforge.net/projects/qt5ct/
And export the following environment variables (i export them from .xinitrc, but you can export them in other files as well..):
export QT_QPA_PLATFORMTHEME=qt5ct export GTK2_RC_FILES=&amp;quot;$HOME/.gtkrc-2.0&amp;quot;  You should also make sure that these lines exist in ~/.config/Trolltech.conf :
[Qt] style=GTK+  Some Qt applications gets updated on the fly, qbittorrent for instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mondo_generate_gtk</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/mondo_generate_gtk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:40:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/mondo_generate_gtk/</guid>
      <description>This is the fifth video in a series on how to setup and use my theme manager, mondo.
In this video i show how i generate GTK themes from the colors set with mondo. It also describes how to add extra actions to the generators in mondo. (the only default action is to generate a file based on the template, in this video I send that generated file to an external GTK generator)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mondo_setup</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/mondo_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:37:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/mondo_setup/</guid>
      <description>This is the second video in a series on how to setup and use my theme manager, mondo.
mondos settings are stored in a directory called MONDO_DIR in the documentation (mondo -h). By default this directory is: ~/.config/mondo but it can be changed with the environment variable.
MONDO_DIR will get created if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist when you execute mondo -n THEME (create a new theme) the first time.
Videos about mondo:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>antidote</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/antidote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:32:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/antidote/</guid>
      <description>This is the first video in a series on how to setup and use my theme manager, mondo.
In this video I try to present my new project: mondo. It&amp;rsquo;s a theme manager, generator that can be used to change themes everywhere .
mondos settings are stored in a directory called MONDO_DIR in the documentation (mondo -h). By default this directory is: ~/.config/mondo but it can be changed with the environment variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>custom_menus_in_rofi</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/custom_menus_in_rofi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:30:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/custom_menus_in_rofi/</guid>
      <description>This is the last in a series of 3 about how to setup rofi.
In this video I create a custom menu that switches the theme in .Xresources that i created in the poison series
mondo These videos, inspired me to create my own theme manager called: mondo . By using mondo the processes shown in these videos can be done in a much more sober way, with more control and more flexibility!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>theming_rofi</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/theming_rofi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:28:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/theming_rofi/</guid>
      <description>This is the second in a series of 3 about how to setup rofi.
In this video we go more in depth on how to configure rofi themes. I use awk and sed to insert values from .Xresources into the theme file.
mondo These videos, inspired me to create my own theme manager called: mondo . By using mondo the processes shown in these videos can be done in a much more sober way, with more control and more flexibility!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>polypoison</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polypoison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:25:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polypoison/</guid>
      <description>This is part 3 of 3 about how to set up colors and fonts using .Xresourcess and syncing the settings in multiple applications.
In this video I apply the settings to polybar.
I have more videos about polybar, a good one to start with is:
#010: polybar setup https://youtu.be/7RNgpvBMua0
I filed an issue regarding fontsetting in polybar here:
https://github.com/jaagr/polybar/issues/954
mondo These poison videos, inspired me to create my own theme manager called: mondo .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rice_of_the_poison</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/rice_of_the_poison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 14:23:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/rice_of_the_poison/</guid>
      <description>This is part 2 of 3 about how to set up colors and fonts using .Xresources and syncing the settings in multiple applications.
In this video I apply the settings to i3wm.
mondo These poison videos, inspired me to create my own theme manager called: mondo . By using mondo the processes shown in these videos can be done in a much more sober way, with more control and more flexibility!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>extreme_i3</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/extreme_i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 10:44:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/extreme_i3/</guid>
      <description>In this video I demonstrate my layout script i3fyra .
If you want to try this layout/script i recommend you watch the next video in this series, where i go more in depth on how it works and how to set it up:
Let&amp;rsquo;s Linux #003: i3fyra
https://youtu.be/t4Tve-xpwus
video info: color scheme: solarized dark, by Ethan Schoonover
terminal font: Fixedsys figlet font: 3d.flf, by xero icon font: fontawesome wallpaper: na</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>advanced_generators</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/advanced_generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/advanced_generators/</guid>
      <description>This is the last video in a series on how to setup and use my theme manager, mondo.
In this video I create a more advanced generator, that merges to files into one settings file when a theme is applied.
The program i use to demonstrate this with, is the touch typing teacher: Klavaro
Klavaros settings are located at:
~/.config/klavaro/preferences.ini
If Klavaro is running when a theme is applied, klavaro will overwrite the new settings when it terminates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mondo_gtk</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/mondo_gtk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:15:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/mondo_gtk/</guid>
      <description>This is the forth video in a series on how to setup and use my theme manager, mondo.
In this video we investigate how GTK update and change theme. In the next video we will generate our own GTK themes with the help of mondo.
I use a small program called: gtkrc-reload. You can also use gtk_reload.py from pywal .
These are the files I create generators for:
 ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mondo_generators</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/mondo_generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:14:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/mondo_generators/</guid>
      <description>This is the third video in a series on how to setup and use my theme manager, mondo.
In this video I walk you through how to create generators and templates.
The command to create a generator is:
mondo -t FILE|NAME [FILE]
If you att a single file as the argument, a directory with the same name as the file will get created inside MONDO_DIR/generators/ . If you don&amp;rsquo;t specify a file, and only a name, it will have the same result except the mondo-template file will be empty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urxvt_reload</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/urxvt_reload/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:13:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/urxvt_reload/</guid>
      <description>In this video I show how to set up a script that reloads URxvt when the settings (.Xresources) are updated.
video info:    color scheme: gruvbox, by morhertz     terminal font: Inconsolata   terminal emulator: URxvt   figlet font: 3d.flf, by xero   filemanager: thunar   icon theme: DamaDamas   gtk theme: numix (solarized dark)   wallpaper: polygon-sky    to start a urxvt daemon process use this command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fonts_are_awesome</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/fonts_are_awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:12:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/fonts_are_awesome/</guid>
      <description>In this video we add icons to polybar. And take an in depth look on how to customize the appearance of the modules in polybar. I use a script that let us chose icons with rofi. The icons are from the excellent icon font, fontawesome.
video info:    color scheme: solarized dark, by Ethan Schoonover     terminal font: Inconsolata   terminal emulator: URxvt   figlet font: 3d.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rofi_setup</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/rofi_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:11:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/rofi_setup/</guid>
      <description>This is the first in a series of 3 about how to setup rofi.
In this first video i show what rofi is, how to install it and how to configure it.
I also take a look at rofis new theme engine.
video info:    color scheme: gruvbox, by morhertz     terminal font: Inconsolata   terminal emulator: URxvt   figlet font: 3d.flf, by xero   filemanager: thunar   icon theme: ePapirus   gtk theme: numix (solarized dark)   wallpaper: polygon-mountain    videos https://youtu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>colors_are_poison</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/colors_are_poison/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:08:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/colors_are_poison/</guid>
      <description>This is part 1 of 3 about how to set up colors and fonts using .Xresources and syncing the settings in multiple applications.
In this first video I will show the basics of setting up .Xresources and how it works.
mondo These poison videos, inspired me to create my own theme manager called: mondo . By using mondo the processes shown in these videos can be done in a much more sober way, with more control and more flexibility!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>polybar_dynamic_title</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_dynamic_title/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:06:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_dynamic_title/</guid>
      <description>This is the last in a series of three videos on how to setup polybar.
The goal of the tutorial is to create a module in polybar that displays the title of the active window, but if one clicks (or send a message via a keybinding or terminal) the title it will instead display the class and instance of the title. I will also show how we by right clicking, title/class/instance will get the clicked information in our clipboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>polybar_hook_modules</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_hook_modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:03:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_hook_modules/</guid>
      <description>This is the second in a series of three videos on how to setup polybar.
The goal of the tutorial is to create a module in polybar that displays the title of the active window, but if one clicks (or send a message via a keybinding or terminal) the title it will instead display the class and instance of the title. I will also show how we by right clicking, title/class/instance will get the clicked information in our clipboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>polybar_setup</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 23:02:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/polybar_setup/</guid>
      <description>This is the first in a series of three on how to setup polybar.
Get more screen real estate by setting up polybar, the budRich way (having it overlay the topmost tiltebar).
video info:    color scheme: solarized dark, by Ethan Schoonover     terminal font: Fixedsys   terminal emulator: URxvt   figlet font: 3d.flf, by xero   filemanager: thunar   icon theme: ePapirus   gtk theme: numix (solarized dark)    videos https://youtu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>automatic_script_creation</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/automatic_script_creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/automatic_script_creation/</guid>
      <description>In this video I show you how to make a script that makes scripts! We also take a look at the $PATH environment variable, what it is and how it works. And how to make a file(script executable by using the chmod command). Finally i demo this by showing how the famous lolban command works.
I use these tools to display colorized ASCII art fonts:
http://caca.zoy.org/wiki/toilet
https://github.com/busyloop/lolcat
video info:    color scheme: solarized dark, by Ethan Schoonover     terminal font: Fixedsys   terminal emulator: URxvt   figlet font: 3d.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3_extreme_size_mode</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/i3_extreme_size_mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:58:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/i3_extreme_size_mode/</guid>
      <description>This is a method to gain full control over windowresizing by combining i3wm&amp;rsquo;s mode function and a simple script.
i3get is used to determine the floating state of the window. i3get is part of the i3ass suite that can be found on github:
https://github.com/budRich/i3ass
The polished version of this script is called i3Kohrne, and is somewhere in my scripts repo on github.
video info:    color scheme: solarized dark, by Ethan Schoonover     terminal font: Fixedsys   terminal emulator: URxvt   figlet font: 3d.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3_rename_instances</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/i3_rename_instances/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:56:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/i3_rename_instances/</guid>
      <description>In this video i show how to rename the instance of a window by using xdotool and some advanced features of my script i3run. The program we experiment with is the filemanager thunar.
i3run is a shell script that lets you run, raise or hide a window or command with a single hotkey in i3wm. It is part of the i3ass suite that can be found on github:
https://github.com/budRich/i3ass</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>minimize_windows_in_i3wm</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/minimize_windows_in_i3wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:55:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/minimize_windows_in_i3wm/</guid>
      <description>In this video i demo my script i3run.
i3run is a shell script that lets you run, raise or hide a window or command with a single hotkey in i3wm. It is part of the i3ass suite that can be found on github:
https://github.com/budRich/i3ass
video info:    color scheme: solarized dark, by Ethan Schoonover     terminal font: Fixedsys   figlet font: 3d.flf, by xero   icon font: fontawesome    In this video I use the program wmctrl to get information about the windows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>more_config_rice</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/more_config_rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:53:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/more_config_rice/</guid>
      <description>This is the second of two videos on how to configure i3 and beautify the config file.
In this episode I continue to rice the i3 config file and ramble a bit about the horrible nordic keyboard layout.
Below is a link to the article on my blog about the the layout, and a solution to it&amp;rsquo;s problems:
https://budrich.github.io/blog/swedish_keyboards/
The other video is called:
Let&amp;rsquo;s Linux #004: rice the config</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rice_the_config</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/rice_the_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:50:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/rice_the_config/</guid>
      <description>This is the first of two videos on how to configure i3 and beautify the config file.
In this episode i show some tricks how to make the i3 config file easier to work with by using variables.
The other video is called:
Let&amp;rsquo;s Linux #005: more config rice
https://youtu.be/OKPvIsurYRI
I have also written an aritcle on my blog about this:
https://budrich.github.io/blog/i3_setup/
Everything I show is also described in detail in the official i3 userguide:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3fyra</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/i3fyra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 19:27:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/letslinux/i3fyra/</guid>
      <description> In this video I show how to setup and use my layoutscript i3fyra
i3fyra and some other i3 related tools can be found in my i3ass github repo:
https://github.com/budRich/i3ass
video info:    color scheme: solarized dark, by Ethan Schoonover     terminal font: Fixedsys   figlet font: 3d.flf, by xero   icon font: fontawesome    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>