<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>i3ass on budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</title>
    <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in i3ass on budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 15:44:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>README</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/readme/</guid>
      <description>i3ass - i3 assistance scripts This is a collection of scripts I have made to assist the usage of the windowmanager known as i3.
installation assinstafina.gif   clone the repository
git clone https://github.com/budRich/i3ass.git
run the installation script
(for further instructions: ./install.sh -h)
./install.sh
usage Execute a script with the -h flag for help.
examples:
i3get -h display i3get help
i3get -v display i3get version
   script function     install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3fyra</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3fyra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3fyra/</guid>
      <description>fyra is the Swedish name for &amp;ldquo;four&amp;rdquo;.
 www.youtube.com/watch?v=kU8gb6WLFk8    .
www.youtube.com/watch?v=t4Tve-xpwus    In the first video above I show the functionality of i3fyra. The second video is a longer and more thorough walkthrough on how to use i3fyra
An advanced simple tiling layout for i3wm. The layout consists of four containers:
 A B C D  The internal layout of the containers doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3list</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3list/</guid>
      <description>This script is vital for i3fyra to work. But it can be used on it&amp;rsquo;s own or with other scripts. i3list is also used by i3run. i3list parses the output of the command: i3-msg -t get_tree and returns a long string with 43 values separated by spaces. This strange output format is made to make it possible to pipe the output to other scripts. A lot of the information is specific to i3fyra, but if i3list doesn&amp;rsquo;t find a value an X will be placed in it&amp;rsquo;s place in the output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3term</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3term/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3term/</guid>
      <description>I just made this script to keep my i3config cleaner. It probably needs tweaking if someone other then budRich uses it ;)
Launch a command in a new urxvt window Uses i3run to run or raise a window with the instancename: COMMAND. If no window is found, COMMAND is ran in a urxvt window with the same instance name as COMMAND. When the command exits window is cleared and returned to bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3zen</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:38:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3zen/</guid>
      <description> I made a post on /r/unixporn where you can view an animated gif of i3zen in action.
Put the window between two ghosts (centered). if the window already is &amp;ldquo;zen&amp;rdquo;, move it back to its original workspace. If the window is not in zen but another window is, both of them will be zen in a tabbed container.
usage
$ i3zen [OPTION] ARGUMENT
   option argument function     -v  show version info and exit   -h  show this help and exit    dependencies  i3get i3gw  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3run</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:36:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3run/</guid>
      <description>This is a run or raise or hide script for i3wm. It looks for a window matching a given criteria.
These are the actions taken depending on the state of the found window:
   target window state action     Active and not handled by i3fyra mark and hide   Active and handled by i3fyra do nothing   Handled by i3fyra and hidden show container, activate   Not handled by i3fyra and hidden show window, activate   Not on current workspace goto workspace   Not found run command    Hidden in this context, means that window is on scratchpad/ Show in this context means, move window to current workspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3mtm</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3mtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:32:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3mtm/</guid>
      <description>When launched without options, i3mtm checks floating status of current window. If it is tiled, the window becomes floating. If it is floating, a search for marks is done, if no marks are found, window becomes tiled. Otherwise a dmenu asks for a mark to move window to. If no selection is made, window is tiled but not moved. Otherwise window is tiled and moved to selected mark.
With -m option window is treaded as if it was floating even if it is tiled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3gw</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3gw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:24:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3gw/</guid>
      <description>In the screenshot below, the windows to the right are tiled, and a ghostwindow is tiled on the left half of the screen. The other windows are floating.
ss-i3gw1.png   A Ghost window wrapper for i3wm.
i3-msg has an undocumented function (open) that creates empty containers, or as I call them: ghosts. Since these empty containers doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain any windows there is no instance/class/title to identify them, making it difficult to control them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3get</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3get/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:22:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3get/</guid>
      <description>Search for windows in i3 tree, return desired information if no arguments are passed. con_id of acitve window is returned.
usage $ i3get [OPTION [CRITERIA]]
   option criteria function     -v  show version and exit   -h  show this help   -a  currently active window (default)   -c CLASS search for windows with the given class   -i INSTANCE search for windows with the given instance   -t TITLE search for windows with title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3cast</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3cast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:20:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/i3ass/i3cast/</guid>
      <description>Create and upload screen recordings
usage $ i3cast [-v|-h]
   option argument function     -v  show version info and exit   -h  show this help and exit    Just run the script to start the recording run it again to stop and preview the recording and perform action, (save,upload or play again). if no action is selected the recording is deleted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>