<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>i3add on budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</title>
    <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/</link>
    <description>Recent content in i3add on budRich.github.io - Boiling rice in coffe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 10:26:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>i3cast</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3cast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 19:30:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3cast/</guid>
      <description>I use this script to create the gifs and videos you see me posting here and on youtube. It has a bunch of dependencies, but they are all good programs and the recording process is very lightweight compared to the other alternatives I&amp;rsquo;ve tried.
Just run the script to start the recording, run it again to preview the video and then chose what to do. (convert to gif, upload, save e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3Kornhe</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3kornhe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 19:29:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3kornhe/</guid>
      <description>This is the polished version of the i3resizemode script i made in one of the Lets Linux episodes. I named it after the moderator on up who banned me for a month after I told a guy to RTFM&amp;hellip;
i3Kornhe - Resize windows by moving the corners. SYNOPSIS i3Kornhe [-v|-h] DIRECTION
DESCRIPTION The script checks if the currently active window is floating. If it is floating the script will acrivate one of four modes depending on the direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3minimize</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3minimize/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 19:27:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3minimize/</guid>
      <description>i3minimize - Minimize active window SYNOPSIS i3minimize [-v|-h]
DESCRIPTION Depending on the state of active window, i3minimize does different things.
   window state action     floating send to scratchpad   tiled, not handled by i3fyra send to scratchpad   tiled, handled by i3fyra hide parent container    OPTIONS -v Show version and exit.
-h Show help and exit.
DEPENDENCIES i3list</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3monocle</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3monocle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 19:26:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3monocle/</guid>
      <description>i3monocle - Maximize active window SYNOPSIS i3monocle [-v|-h] [-g]
DESCRIPTION i3monocle Will first check the floating state of the active window. If it is floating, i3fyra -a (autolayot/toggle tiling) will get invoked to ensure the window is tiled and in a i3fyra container. Then all other visible i3fyra containers will get hidden. Leaving the active window in monocle (maximized) mode.
If the window is already monocled, it will be put in ZenMode with i3zen if not the -g flag is passed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3term</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3term/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 19:24:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3term/</guid>
      <description>I just made this script to keep my i3config cleaner. It probably needs tweaking if someone other then budRich uses it ;)
i3term - Launch a command in a new urxvt window SYNOPSIS i3term [-v|-h] COMMAND
DESCRIPTION Uses i3run to run or raise a window with the instancename: COMMAND. If no window is found, COMMAND is ran in a urxvt window with the same instance name as COMMAND. When the command exits window is cleared and returned to bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3wswp</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3wswp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 19:22:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3wswp/</guid>
      <description>i3wswp - Switch workspace and wallpaper SYNOPSIS i3wswp [-v|-h] WORKSPACE
DESCRIPTION i3wswp takes a WORKSPACE number as an argument. If there exist a non empty ENVIRONMENT varialbe with the name I3WSWP_COMMAND_WORKSPACE . The content of that variable will be executed. i3wswp is intended to be used with some kind of subscriber script and be executed on workspace change.
OPTIONS -v
Show version and exit.
-h
Show help and exit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3zen</title>
      <link>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 19:22:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://budrich.github.io/scripts/i3add/i3zen/</guid>
      <description>I made a post on /r/unixporn where you can view an animated gif of i3zen in action.
i3zen - Send windows to the zenter SYNOPSIS i3zen [-v|-h]
DESCRIPTION Put the active window in a tabbed container between two ghostswindows (centered) on a clean workspace. If the window already is in ZenMode, move it back to it&amp;rsquo;s original workspace. If the window is not in zen but another window is, both of them will be zen in a tabbed container.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>